Emanuel Ruben Piore Papers ca.1918-1986 Mss.Ms.Coll.80
American Philosophical Society
- Series III. Speeches, 1951-1982; 5 boxes; 2.5 linear feet (Box Series III: 1-5)
  - Outline of Remarks at University of Dayton Kickoff Dinner, 1956 April 28; 12 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Remarks to Stockholders, 1956 April 12; 1 item; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Talk before the National Telemetering Conference in Los Angeles, 1956 August 22; 11 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Technology: USA and Russia, 1956 March 14; 1 item; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - American Management Association Seminar, 1957 November 20-22; 4 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Electronics in the Limited War, 1957 December 4; 12 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Extracts of Speeches at Williamsburg Conference, 1957 February 7; 3 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Philosophy of Research in IBM, 1957 February 4; 5 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Research Leading to Future Computers, 1957 November 8; 4 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Electronic Research, 1958 March-April; 1 item; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - The Next Decade in Engineering, 1958 May 19; 11 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Organization for Research, 1958 October 9; 15 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Science and National Policy, 1958 December 17; 5 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Suggested Remarks for Dr. E.R. Piore's Talk at Peekskill Presbyterian Church, 1958 June 3; 3 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Computer Science and Technolgy in Industry: Future Promise and Problems, 1959 September 18; 7 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Dedication of Science Building: Riverdale Country School for Boys, 1959 May 25; 5 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - [Federal Council of Science and Technology], 1959 May-April; 2 folders; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
    - Folder 1, 1959 May; 4 items
    - Folder 2, 1959 April; 10 items
  - Future Computers and their Origins, 1959 September 18; 3 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - How Much Creativity can Industry Afford, 1959 September 29; 6 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - National Conference on the Administration of Research, 1959 October; 2 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - National Policy on Science: Its Formulation and Financing, 1959 May 25; 12 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Organizing for Research, 1959 April; 4 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Scientific Creativity, 1959 July; 11 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - The Spectrum of Research Organizations, 1959 April 20; 11 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Why Industrial Research, 1959 June 3; 1 item; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Challenging Developments in the Relationship of Government to, 1960; 2 folders; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
    - Folder 1, 1960; 15 items
    - Folder 2, 1960; 11 items
  - Disarmament and the American Economy, 1960 July 12; 1 item; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - IBM Research, 1960 October; 1 item; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Talk for Scientific American Meeting, 1960; 10 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Teaching and Learning and Machines, 1960 December 30; 1 item; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - 100% Club Talk, 1961 January; 4 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Appraising the Company's Technical Efforts, 1961; 11 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - The Challenge of Science to World Leadership, 1961 June 14; 6 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - The Changing Picture of Government Support of Science and, 1961; 9 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Mechines that Teach and Learn, 1961; 3 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Management and the Computer of the Future, 1961 May 16; 15 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Physics and Engineering in a Free Society, 1961March; 1 item; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Pre-symposium address, 1961 May; 14 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Reseach and Development, 1961 May 18; 11 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - The Role of Basic Research in Communications and Electronics, 1961August 1; 13 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Science and National Policy, 1961 December 7; 7 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Technologies for the FutureComputers, 1961 December 8; 7 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Miscellaneous, 1961; 6 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Instrumentation and Computers, 1962 October 15; 1 item; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - The Partnership between Science and Electrical Engineering, 1962; 5 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - The Role of Basic Research in Communications and Electronics, 1962 May 5; 2 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Tomorrow's Engineers: What Society will Require, 1962; 4 folders; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
    - Folder 1, 1961 December-1962 July; 7 items
    - Folder 2, 1962 September; 8 items
    - Folder 3, 1962 October; 11 items
    - Folder 4, 1962; 1 item
  - Views on Technological Change, 1962 May 5; 6 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - 6th IBM Medical Symposium: Introductory Remarks, 1964 October 5; 2 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Computing and Solid State Machines, 1964; 1 item; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Department of Defense and Industry Relationships, 1964; 21 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - The Engineers Role in Expanding the Economy, 1964 May 4; 11 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - The Impact of New Materials and New Instrumentation on our Foreseeable Technology, 1964; 4 folders; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
    - Folder 1, 1964; 9 items
    - Folder 2, 1964; 4 items
    - Folder 3, 1964; 5 items
    - Folder 4, 1964; 26 items
  - The Professor's Responsibilty, 1964; 1 item; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Science in our Society, 1964 February 23; 1 item; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Miscellaneous, 1964; 2 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Department of Defense/Industrial Relationship, 1965; 20 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Eta Kappa Nu Association: Award Dinner, 1965; 2 folders; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
    - Folder 1, 1965; 12 items
    - Folder 2, 1965; 21 items
  - Remarks on Defense Industry Advisory Council, 1965 March 16; 3 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Science and Man's Future, 1965; 19 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Science and Public Interest, 1965 December 15; 2 folders; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
    - Folder 1, 1965 December 15; 8 items
      Includes to Photograph of Piore speaking. Removed to Series
    - Folder 2, 1965 December 15; 21 items
  - Science, Research and a look ahead., 1965 May 12; 5 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Systems and Hardware, 1965; 2 folders; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
    - Folder 1, 1965; 18 items
    - Folder 2, 1965; 4 items
  - Talk at the Meeting of National Security Industrial Association, 1965 March 16; 4 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Technology Management in the USSR and How it Relates to, 1965 April 15; 6 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - University Seminar on Technological and Social Change, 1965; 3 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Miscellaneous, 1965; 2 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Big Science, Small Science, 1966 March 22; 10 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - The Building Blocks of Tomorrow's Technology, 1966; 2 folders; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
    - Folder 1, 1966; 9 items
    - Folder 2, 1966; 14 items
  - The Computer Revolution, 1966 February 28; 3 folders; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
    - Folder 1, 1966; 9 items
    - Folder 2, 1966; 1 item
    - Folder 3, 1966; 23 items
  - Man's Technical Resources, Past, Present, and Future., 1966; 14 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - National Security Industrial Association Advanced Planning Briefings for Industry, 1966 April 27; 4 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Science - Industry and Government, 1966; 11 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Science in the Post-Industrial Era, 1966 April 13; 14 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Worthington Worldwide Managers of Engineering Meeting, 1966 May 16; 10 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - The Problems of a Large Accelerator Laboratory, 1967 March 2; 15 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Science and Technology in Industry, 1967 October 17; 3 folders; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
    - Folder 1, 1967; 14 items
    - Folder 2, 1967; 7 items
    - Folder 3, 1967; 3 items
  - Statement of Dr. Emanuel R. Piore before the Subcommittee on Administrative Practice and Procedure, 1967 March 15; 2 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Visibility in Industrial Research, 1967 May 30; 5 folders; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
    - Folder 1, 1967; 10 items
    - Folder 2, 1967; 10 items
    - Folder 3, 1967; 17 items
      Includes photograph of Piore, receiving award, and two unidentified men. Removed to Series V
    - Folder 4, 1967; 7 items
    - Folder 5, 1967; 16 items
  - "Information Processing" in Industry, 1968; 15 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Technion Talk, 1968 December 5; 23 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - 10th Symposium on Electron, Ion, and Laser Beam Technology, 1969 May 21; 5 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Challenges and Progress in Computing: People, Technology, 1969; 4 folders; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
    - Folder 1, 1969; 8 items
    - Folder 2, 1969; 19 items
    - Folder 3, 1969; 5 items
    - Folder 4, 1969; 21 items
  - Daddario Committee Testimony, 1969 October 7; 6 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Establishment of a Natinal Science Research Data Processing and Information Retrieval System, 1969 April 25; 3 folders; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
    - Folder 1, 1969; 4 items
    - Folder 2, 1969; 16 items
    - Folder 3, 1969; 2 items
  - Keynote Address, 1969 September 29; 5 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - The Potentiality of Science. Now and in the 21st Century, 1969; 9 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - The Relationship Between Science and Technology in the Industrial Environment, 1969 June 23; 7 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Technological Innovation: Master or Servant?, 1969 March 6; 3 folders; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
    - Folder 1, 1969; 16 items
    - Folder 2, 1969; 11 items
    - Folder 3, 1969; 7 items
  - Continuing Education and Corporate Growth in a Technical Society, 1970 September 10; 2 folders; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
    - Folder 1, 1970; 2 items
    - Folder 2, 1970; 14 items
  - Future of Computing, 1970 February 25; 1 item; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - National Science Policy, 1970 August 14; 6 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Science and Engineering in the 1970's, 1970 May 27; 17 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - The Scienctist and Politics, 1971 March 11; 31 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Science and National Policy, 1973 November 18; 3 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - William E. Wiener Oral History Library Luncheon, 1973 May 19; 3 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - ATS Research and Development Meeting, 1975 January 20; 1 item; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Eugene F. Kinkead, 1975; 1 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Interview, 1975; 2 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - National Science Foundation after twenty five years, 1975; 6 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - The Development of United States Science Policy since World War II, 1976 November 2; 2 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Remarks made at the Commencement Exercises at Herbert Lehman College, [1976 June 2]; 2 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Science and Industry, 1976 February 19; 2 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Scientific Advice at the White House, 1976 January 29; 6 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - University of California, 1976 January 29; 1 item; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Technion, 1977 June 8; 3 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - 1980 April 21, 2 items; Computers-Present and future: Introduction to the symposium
  - 1981, 2 items; Physics Funding-the Evolving Federal Role
  - 1982, 1 item; Science, Government, and Policy: a Four-Decade Perspective.
  - Notes on Department of Defense and Universities in Research and Development, 1 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Remarks before the General Advisory Committee of the Atomic Energy Commission, n.d.; 1 item; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Research and Development, 6 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - The Role of Scientific Research in the Development of New Weapons by the Navy, n.d.; 1 item; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - The Role of Scientific Research and Development in Warfare - Past, Present, and Future., 2 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Talk before Reserve Groups Working in Intelligence Agencies, n.d.; 2 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
  - Miscellaneous Speeches, n.d.; 3 items; Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000
- Series IV. Finacial Records, 1955-1972; 3 boxes; 1.5 linear feet (Box Series IV: 1-3)
  Financial records including Piore's tax returns and stock options.
  - Income Tax Material, 1955; 2 folders; 31 items
  - Income Tax Material, 1957; 30 items
  - Income Tax Material, 1958; 30 items
  - Income Tax Material, 1959; 30 items
  - Income Tax Material, 1960; 30 items
  - Income Tax Material, 1961; 25 items
  - Income Tax Material, 1962; 2 folders; 41 items
  - Income Tax Material, 1963; 2 folders; 54 items
  - Income Tax Material, 1964; 2 folders; 55 items
  - Income Tax Material, 1965; 2 folders; 50 items
  - Income Tax Material, 1966; 26 items
  - Income Tax Material, 1967; 3 folders; 78 items
  - Income Tax Material, 1968; 3 folders; 85 items
  - Income Tax Material, 1969; 4 folders; 111 items
  - Income Tax Material, 1970; 30 items
  - Income Tax Material, 1971; 3 folders; 90 items
  - Paid Bills, 1971; 2 folders; 60 items
  - Stock, 1956-1972; 24 folders
    - Health Advancement Technology, 1970-1974; 27 items
    - Intercontinental Oil Corporation, 1969-1970; 6 items
    - Intercontinental Technology and Natural Resources S.A., 1969; 3 items
    - International Business Machine Corporation, 1956-1971; 8 folders
      - Folder 1, 1956-1959; 20 items
      - Folder 2, 1960-1963; 25 items
      - Folder 3, 1964-1965; 24 items
      - Folder 4, 1966-1967; 23 items
      - Folder 5, 1968; 35 items
      - Folder 6, 1969; 30 items
      - Folder 7, 1970; 14 items
      - Folder 8, 1971; 18 items
    - Magna Corporation, 1968-1971; 14 items
    - Mass Feeding Corporation, 1970; 2 folders
      - Folder 1, 1969-1970 May; 10 items
      - Folder 2, 1970 June-1971; 10 items
    - Microwire Corporation, 1970-1971; 4 folders
      - Folder 1, 1970 February; 1 item
      - Folder 2, 1970 February; 1 item
      - Folder 3, 1970 March-December; 10 items
      - Folder 4, 1971; 10 items
    - Neuberger and Berman, 1955-1970; 25 items
    - Pentech, inc., 1970-1971; 5 items
    - Steam Engine Systems Corporation, 1969-1971; 5 items
    - Surface Activation Corporation, 1970-1972; 3 folders
      - Folder 1, 1970; 6 items
      - Folder 2, 1972; 3 items
      - Folder 3, 1972; 4 items
    - Whitney Operations, 1969-1970; 10 items
- Series V. Photographs, ca. 1918-1982; 6 boxes; 1 linear foot (Box Series V: 1-6)
  Miscellaneous personal and professional photographs including family photographs, numerous studio and informal portraits of Piore, and informal and formal group photographs. A number of unidentifed photograph are also found in this series.
  - American Institute of Physics -- Meeting of the Governing Board, 1965 March 20; 1 item
  - Avco's Advanced Scientific Executive Committee, [ca. 1950]; 1 item
    oversize, 11 x 14 box
  - Avco Manufacturing Corporation -- Dinner, 1956; 3 items
  - Bronk, Detlev W. (Detlev Wulf), 1897- 1975, n.d.; 1 item
    studio portrait
    Removed from series I; [Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-200]. Detlev Wulf Bronk: The Transition from war to peace.
  - California Institute of Technology, [ca. 1950]; 1 item
    Piore standing with a group of unidentified men listening to talk.
  - Chemistry and Physics of Metals -- Conference, 1953 July 12-17; 3 items
    Removed from Series I; American Institute of Physics.
  - Courant, Richard, 1888-1972., n.d.; 2 items
  - Davidson, Joan -- Chairman of N.Y. State Council on the Arts, n.d.; 1 item
    Informal portrait
    Removed from series I, Bronk, Detlev W. folder.
  - Sidney Davis, Alexander Kahn, Estes Kefauver, and S. Regensberg, 1956 August; 1 item
  - Defense Science Board -- 1st Meeting, 1956 September 20; 1 item
  - Ann and May Dyer, 1943 December; 1 item
  - East Coast Senior Scienctists -- Visit to U.S. Naval Proving Ground, Dahlgren, Va., 1953 February 2; 1 item
  - Fanya -- Piore's Aunt, negative, n.d.; 1 item
    negative
  - Fredman Family, 1982 January; 1 item
    Removed from Series I; Fredman, Mario.
  - International Business Machines Corporation, n.d.; 1 item
    Photograph of building
  - International Business Machines Corporation -- Board of Directors, n.d.; 1 item
    Removed from Series II; Board of Directors.
  - Joint Technical Advisory Committee -- Meeting, 1967; 2 items
    Removed from Series I; Institute of Electrical Engineers, folder 1.
  - Manila, P. I. -- Diplomatic and Military Leaders are Escorted to Philippine, 1946 July 30; 1 item
  - Mohansic Laboratory -- Visit, 1960 June 30; 1 item
    Group Photograph of W. J. Rowland, R. Lilly, George P. Sutton, Emanuel Piore, A. W. Betts, J. C. Jones and V. Parnell.
  - National Science Board (U.S.), [ca. 1960]; 3 items
    removed from Series I; National Science Board.
  - Niels Bohr Library -- Meeting of the Governing Board of the AIP, 1974 March 23; 1 item
  - Pina [?] -- Olga Piore's oldest brother., n.d.; 1 item
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Canadian Aviation Electronics, n.d.; 3 items
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Contact sheets, [ca. 1965-1985]; 5 items
    Housed in oversized, 11 x 14 box.
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Emanuel R. Piore Award, n.d.; 3 items
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Family dinner, Canton, Ohio, 1961 June 7; 1 item
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Gold Medal of Industrial Research award, 1967; 1 item
    Removed from Series III; Visibility in Industrial Research, 1967,
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Indentification card, Philadelphia Naval Yard, 1 item
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Informal Portrait, [ca. 1950-1960]; 1 item
    Piore, standing at bookshelf holding pipe.
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Informal Portrait, [ca. 1950-1960]; 4 items
    Piore seated smoking pipe.
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Informal Portrait, 1960 August 30; 2 folders
    - Folder 1, 1960 August 30; 4 items
      Four photographs of Piore on the phone and smoking pipe most likely taken at IBM.
    - Folder 2, 1960 August 30; 2 items
      Two photographs of Piore reading most likely taken at IBM.
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Informal Portrait, [ca. 1960]; 3 items
    Piore seated at desk holding papers.
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Informal Portrait, [ca. 1960]; 2 folders
    Piore seated behind desk
    - Folder 1, [ca. 1960]; 4 items
    - Folder 2, [ca. 1960]; 7 items
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Informal Portrait, [ca. 1960]; 2 items
    Piore standing at chalk board.
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Informal Portrait, [ca. 1960]; 1 item
    Piore seated behind desk holding pipe.
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Informal Portrait, 1964 February 11; 2 items
    Piore seated holding pipe
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Informal Portrait, [ca. 1965]; 2 folders
    - Folder 1, [ca. 1965]; 5 items
    - Folder 2, [ca. 1965]; 5 items
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Informal portrait, 1966 January 13; 2 items
    Piore seated on sofa. Piore seated on sofa writing.
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Tour of IBM Pavilion, 1958 July 16; 3 items
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Japan, n.d.; 4 items
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Kaplun Award, [1976]; 4 items
    Removed from Series I; Universitah ha-Ivrit Bi-Yerushalayim, folder
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Krantz, Morry and Emanuel Piore, 1974; 1 item
    Krantz and Piore, profile, standing, informal, with Piore smoking
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- National Science Foundation, questionnaire, 1962 June 18; 2 items
    Piore seated at desk writing.
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Negatives, [ca. 1965-1985]; 4 items
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Passport photograph, [ca. 1970-1980]; 3 items
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Nora and Emanuel Piore seated at table, 1 item
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Nora Piore, Emanuel Piore and six unidentified women and one man standing on board the Queen Mary, 1 item
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Olga, Emanuel and Michael Piore, standing outside, 1 item
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Olga and Emanuel Piore, studio portait, [ca. 1918]; 1 item
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Poughkeepsie dinner, 1960; 4 items
    Piore standing among dinner tables, informal
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Professor Malcolm [?] and Emanuel Piore, 1 item
    Malcolm and Piore seated, informal with Piore smoking pipe.
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Reception for Carl Alpert, 1983 January 25; 1 item
    Removed from Series I; Tekhniyon, makhon tekhnologi le-Yisra'el.
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Russotto family and Emanuel Piore in Edgemere, L. I., studio potrait, [ca. 1918]; 1 item
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Russotto, Leo and 11 unidentified children seated on steps, [ca. 1920]; 1 item
    Removed from Series I; Russotto, Leo
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Slide, n.d.; 1 item
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Sony Chairman of the Board and Emanuel Piore, 1 item
    Sony Chairman and Piore, profile, standing, informal
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Speech; Science and Public Interest, 1965 December 15; 2 items
    Removed from Series III; Science and Public Interest, folder 1.
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Studio Portrait, [ca. 1935-40]; 3 items
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Studio Portrait, [ca. 1950-1955]; 4 items
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Studio Portrait, [ca. 1950-1960]; 6 items
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Studio Portrait, [ca. 1955-1965]; 2 folders
    - Folder 1, [ca. 1955-1965]; 5 items
    - Folder 2, [ca. 1955-1965]; 5 items
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Studio Portrait, [ca. 1965]; 1 item
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Studio Portrait, [ca. 1975]; 3 items
    smoking pipe
    One copy removed from Series I; New York Hall of Science, folder
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- White House Greeting of industrial research leaders, 1964 December 15; 2 folders
    - Folder 1, 1964 December 15; 4 items
      Piore, Dr. J. Herbert Holloman, Dr. Robert L. Hershey, and President Johnson seated, informal at White House
    - Folder 2, 1964 December 15; 6 items
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Woods Hole Visit, 1954; 2 items
    Piore, Ed H. Smith and two unidentified men seated at table,
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Unidentifed awards ceremony, n.d.; 5 items
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Unidentifed awards ceremony, n.d.; 3 items
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Unidentifed awards ceremony, n.d.; 1 item
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Unidentified conference, n.d.; 1 item
    Group photograph outside in front of building